Swapnil A Mehta

Sales & Marketing

Astute Branch Manager with 11 years Sales & Marketing experience looking to obtain a position where outstanding communication and problemsolving talents can be fully utilized. Positive, ambitious, flexible and motivational. Proven background in providing supervision and development opportunities to associates. Excellent communicator with aptitude for defusing high-pressure situations.

Contact

Address

E03, Takshashila Appt, Nr Mansi Cross Road, Vastrapur, Satellite Ahmedabad, Gujarat, 310015

Phone

989-839-1962

E-mail

swapnilamehta@gmail.com

D.O.B

25-03-1990

Skills

Branch Management



Channel Management



Education

2010-01 -

MBA: Marketing

2012-01

S.V.Institute Of Management, Technological

University - Kadi,

Marks - 79%

2007-01 -2010-01 **Bachelor of Commerce**

S.M. Patel Institute of Commerce - SMPIC -

Ahmedabad Marks - 64%

....

Work History

2016-06 Current - Regional Head

Bajaj Electricals LTD, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Work Profile (1st Nov 2022 to Till Date): Regional Head: Surat Branch

- A) Managing the portfolio of 80 90CR P.A. This includes products like FANS / Water Heater / Kitchen appliances /Coolers etc.
- B) Handling the Team of 12 on roll employee and 15+ off roll employees

Sales & Cost

Management

Excellent

Team

Management Excellent

Sales Planning and Targeting

Excellent

Languages

English, Hindi, Gujarati

Hobbies

- Painting Cartoons
- Organizing Parties & Ever
- Cheesy Food

- C) Direct all operational aspects along with sales i.e distribution operations, customer service, human resource, Marketing etc.
- D) Bring out the best of branch's personnel by providing training, coaching, development, and motivation
- E) Locate areas of improvement and take corrective actions like channel correction, analysis market trend and proposing scheme / marketing activities etc.

Work Profile (1st Dec 2018 to Oct'22): Area Head Marketing - Gujarat:

- A) Collaborated with sales department and marketing team to create strategies to Boost up Sales along with profitability.
- B) Appointing & launching of new distributor
- C) Strengthened product-branding initiatives by developing communication campaigns, promotional materials, market intelligence information and databases for Gujarat market to maximize outreach.
- D) Directed and launched more than 20+ product & additions of new market expansion.
- E) **Recommended product changes** to enhance customer interest and maximize sales.
- F) Organized Road Shows, Trade Fair, Dealer Meets etc.
- G) Optimized point-of-sale campaigns to engage consumers for traffic-generation and sales conversion.
- H) Training & MIS management

Work Profile (11th June 2016 to 30th Nov 2018): Territory Head, Ahmadabad & North Gujarat

- A) Managed day-to-day operations, including supervision and assigned delegation for 3+8member team.
- B) Maintaining the hygiene of existing channel partners & appointment of new channel partners.

- C) Grew MR Business from **15lacs -76lacs p.m.** Also Developed and implemented strategies to drive same business, maintaining budgetary (Secondary/Primary) guidelines.
- E) Recruited, hired and trained new employees, including monitoring and review of individual performance.

2015-01 - Area Manager

2016-06

IFB Industries Limited, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Work Profile: Territory Sales Manager, Bhavnagar, Amreli

- A) Achieved 200% increase in sales revenue with Rs
 3.0 to 3.5 CR pm.
- A) Audited Bhavnagar sales performance and data trends to improve underperforming areas.
- B) Planned and developed strategies to increase sales and territory.
 - C) Formalized sales process to enhance operations and promote acquisition of new dealers/Distributor.
 - D) Innovative ideas to boost up to product line.
 - F) Formularize strategy brand awareness initiatives.

2012-08 - Channel Manager

2014-12

Vodafone west Limited, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Work Profile: Channel Manager, Baroda/Surat/ /Ahmedabad

- A) Met with each associate to establish realistic monthly sales goals.
- B) Established, enforced, and updated policies keeping business agile, responsive to changing market conditions.
- C) Identified new markets for penetration by carefully researching potential customers' buying habits.
- D) Continuously surpassed sales goals, optimizing profitability, performance of assigned territory.
- E) Planned Strategies to reach the Revenue of 2.5 CR
 P.M

Awards & Achievements

• Academic

- Gold Medal in Marketing from Institute
- 1st Position in various Budget Analysis, Paper presentation, Product Launch, Case analysis etc

Work

- Pygmalion High Potential Employee Hunt (Bajaj)
- 1 Sarvottam Award (Bajaj)
- Employee of the year Marketing (Bajaj)
- 8 Achievers Awards (Bajaj)
- 4 Pride Award (Bajaj)
- Feel Good Contest Winner (Bajaj)
- Super Star Awards (IFB)
- Walk of Fame (Vodafone)
- Best Employee of Month & Quarter (Vodafone)